# Sanjeev Kumar

Masters in Cloud Computing, University of Leicester, UK

Enthusiastic IT professional in building web applications, scripts, and databases with 2.5 years of work experience. I have a range of technical and interpersonal skills that enable me to interact with a wide range of clients. Aim to learn, work, and achieve more as a developer

xk814@student.le.ac.uk

22 Norman street, Leicester, UK

in linkedin.com/in/sanjeev-singh1

## +44 7774081892

sk814.pythonanywhere.com/

github.com/sk814

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **ETL DevOps**

Gemini Solutions Private Limited as Pimco Consultant, US ♂

07/2017 - 12/2019 Gurugram, India Gemini Solutions is an IT Consulting and Product Development firm

Major Role/Projects

- Maintaining and modifying existing scripts, Data Warehousing, Automation of daily tasks using python.
- Extracting financial data from different vendors with various sources and load it into the Databases using scripts.
- Designed tool using python and bash scripting to monitor few critical config files.
- Creating/Maintaining metadata entries of processes in Database.
- Debugging the issues occurred while loading the data into the database.

## Internship

#### Prezotech Solutions Private Limited

11/2016 – 03/2017 Prezotech is Software and Barcode Manufacturer startup Delhi,India

Event Management web application

- Worked on back end designing and implementation of the web application to store and manage the attendance and other details of the guests attending the events organized by the mediator.
- Application has been used in 4 live events and will use in the future as well.
- It is compatible with mobile as well and stored data can be downloaded in excel format and can be used for reporting.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Masters in Cloud Computing**

University of Leicester, UK

01/2020 - Present Leicester

#### **Computer Science Engineering**

G.L Bajaj, A.P.J Abdul Kalam Technical University

06/2014 - 04/2017 India 72% (1st ("First Class"))

## **Polytechnic in CSE**

Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education, Nagpur

06/2011 - 04/2014 India,77%1st ("First Class")

#### 10th

D.A.V Public School (CBSE Board), Patna

03/2011 India 7.8 Grade (1st ("First Class"))

## **IT SKILLS**



# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### Personal page 🗷

- Personal page developed using Django, SQLite HTML, Bootstrap4, and was hosted on python anywhere.
- It have information about me and some link of my social networks. It is compatible with every screens.
- Web app has a reader portal on which users can share the link of some interesting blogs for other users to read. Additionally it is fully back-end controlled

#### Prezotech feedback page ♂

- This web page is used by Prezotech company to take feedback from their clients after sells and service by sharing the link via mail or whatsApp.
- Page was developed using Django, Bootstrap4, CSS, MySQL, and hosted on Cpanel.
- I have used fontawsome, showcase sliders, video play, testimonials and other creative things to give this page look and feel.

#### Sanjeev's Writing 🗷

- It's a portal for users to write and read.
- It is developed using Django, SQLite, Bootstrap4, and hosted on python anywhere.
- Users can make their accounts, create there own content, and also archive there writing which will be hidden from other users.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Received on the spot award from Gemini Solutions for working for 13+ hours due to huge production failure.

Received first prize in a debate on class level in diploma

## **LANGUAGES**

English: Fluent

Hindi: Fluent

#### INTERESTS

